# **Michael Shostrand**

Denver, CO| 314-420-5552 | michael.shostrand@gmail.com | Linkedin.com/in/michael-shostrand/

#### **SUMMARY**

My goal is to find a challenging opportunity in the Denver area where I can utilize my skills and experience to develop efficient, pragmatic solutions that exceed the expectations of external customers and help achieve internal goals.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

June 2016 - July 2020

#### Software Engineer II - Aviation UI, Garmin, Olathe, Kansas

In addition to my Engineer I Responsibilities:

- Planned and delivered three major upgrade programs for the Embraer Phenom aircraft as lead software engineer which earned the company multiple Supplier of the Year awards.
- Implemented new display protocol on the Garmin Touchscreen Controller aviation product to enable expansion into a new market segment.
- Improved performance of Python developer tools resulting in a 10x reduction in deliverable build times.
- Debugged urgent production line and field issues.
- Mentored interns and new hires through a company mentorship program.

June 2015 - June 2016

## Software Engineer I - Aviation UI, Garmin, Olathe, Kansas

- Designed and implemented components of pilot UI for the Garmin G5000 integrated flight deck in an embedded C environment.
- Improved embedded HTML rendering engine enabling widespread use throughout the system for page creation resulting in greatly reduced overhead when making changes.
- Designed UI framework used to create configuration pages for new products and personally used it to integrate five new products into the system.
- Used unit and integration testing to meet stringent FAA testing requirements.

June 2014 - August 2014

#### **Software Engineer Intern - Aviation UI**, Garmin, Olathe, Kansas

- Worked in a large team of interns to test the kernel used in the new Garmin G1000 NXi product.
- Wrote module tests in C using inhouse test framework.
- Made small improvements to the UI of the Garmin Touchscreen Controller product.

July 2013 - August 2013

### Software Engineer Intern, Intelispend Prepaid Solutions, Fenton, Missouri

- Designed a support page in Ruby on Rails to aid customer support.
- Created necessary services on Java backend utilizing Spring and Hibernate.
- Created tables and stored procedures needed for support page using Transact SQL.
- Used Watir scripts to create an automatic test suite for one of the company's web pages.

## Languages

C, Python, Java, C++, SQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS, PHP

## Libraries/Frameworks

PyTorch, React, Node.js, Spring, Hibernate

## **Tools**

Git, SVN, Jira

## **Database Management**

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

## **EDUCATION**

2011 - 2015

# University of Missouri - Columbia, Missouri

Bachelor's of Science, Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics, GPA 3.85

Received Bright Flight Scholarship and Excellence Award

## **INTERESTS**

- Rock Climbing
- Hiking/Backpacking
- Traveling